Guide to the Raymond Family papers, 1855-1947.
Raymond Family papers, 1855-1947.
Division of Rare and Manuscript Collections, Cornell University Library
Raymond Family papers, 1855-1947.
2163
Raymond family.
1 cubic ft.
Accounts.
Division of Rare and Manuscript Collections, Cornell University Library
Farm produce, fruit, crop, labor, pasturage, household and personal accounts of a Penfield, Monroe County New York family.
COLLECTION DESCRIPTION
Farm produce, fruit, crop, labor, pasturage, household and personal accounts of a Penfield, Monroe County New York family.
SUBJECTS
Names:
Raymond family.
Subjects:
Family--New York (State)--Monroe County.; Finance, Personal.; Agriculture.
Places:
Penfield (N.Y.)--Social life and customs.
INFORMATION FOR USERS
CONTAINER LIST
- Series I. Farm produce and labor accounts, 9 vols., 1855-1926
  - R.B. Smith, 1855-1879
    - Farm produce, 1855-1857 (Volume 1)
    - Farm labor, 1855-1857 (Volume 1)
    - Butter & Cheese Account, 1857 (Volume 1)
    - Cash Account, 1857-1865 (Volume 1)
    - Auction of R.B. Smith estate, 1874 (Volume 1)
  - [C.C. Raymond ?], 1864-1926
    - Farm produce, equipment, and items, 1864-1926 (Volume 2)
    - Farm labor (employees - pay rates), 1907-1926 (Volume 2)
    - Personal family and household items (esp. 1910), 1907-1926 (Volume 2)
    - Cash account, 1907-1926 (Volume 2)
    - R. Gould account, 1865-1866 (Volume 2)
    - A. Bennett account, 1866 (Volume 2)
    - Charles Watson account, 1866 (Volume 2)
  - C.C. Raymond, 1866-1891
    - Farm produce, equipment, and items - cash accounts (Bills Paid), 1866-1891 (Volume 3)
    - Farm labor (employees - pay rates) - cash accounts (Bills Paid), 1866-1891 (Volume 3)
    - Personal family items - cash accounts (Bills Paid), 1866-1891 (Volume 3)
    - Apple and grape accounts, 1887-1890 (Volume 3)
    - Cow pasture accounts, 1890 (Volume 3)
    - Strawberry (1886), potato (1887), and raspberry (1885) accounts, 1885-1887 (Volume 3)
  - C.C. Raymond, 1866-1900
    - Farm labor (employees - pay rates), 1866-1867 (Volume 4)
    - Farm produce, equipment, and items, 1891-1900 (Volume 4)
    - Personal family items, 1891-1900 (Volume 4)
    - Dry house accounts, 1891-1898 (Volume 4)
    - Account with W.R. Smith Est., 1893-1895 (Volume 4)
    - Geo. W. Raymond account, 1896-1897 (Volume 4)
  - C.C. Raymond, 1874-1883
    - Farm produce (Volume 5)
    - Personal family items (Volume 5)
    - Farm labor (employees - pay rates), 1876-1881 (Volume 5)
    - Other expenses, 1876-1880 (Volume 5)
  - M.R. Smith, 1876-1901
    - Mill accounts, 1876-1892 (Volume 6)
    - Farm account, 1895-1897 (Volume 6)
    - Personal family accounts, 1884-1885 (Volume 6)
    - Cash accounts, 1883-1895 (Volume 6)
    - Saw Mill accounts, 1894-1901 (Volume 6)
      - M.R. Smith - tenant of C.C. Raymond (C.C. Raymond's wife's maiden name: Francella Smith) (Volume 6)
    - Town of Penfield Accounts, 1897-1898 (Volume 6)
    - Penfield School Orders, 1896-1897 (Volume 6)
    - C.C. Raymond account with Town of Penfield, 1895-1897 (Volume 6)
  - Geo. W. Raymond, 1879-1925
    - Farm produce, and items, 1879 (Volume 7)
    - Personal family items, 1879-1887 (Volume 7)
    - H.M. Stewart account, 1925 (Volume 7)
      - Personal items (Volume 7)
      - Accounts for boarding (Volume 7)
    - Geo. W. Raymond accounts, 1879-1880 (Volume 7)
      - Cash accounts (Volume 7)
      - Company cash accounts (Volume 7)
    - C.E. Preston Accounts, 1876-1883 (Volume 7)
      - Farm produce (Volume 7)
  - C.C. Raymond & Rich, 1880-1897
    - Farm produce, equipment, and items (Volume 8)
    - Farm labor (employees' - pay) (Volume 8)
    - Dry House account kept by Grace D. Raymond (Volume 8)
  - C.C. Raymond, 1887-1907
    - Farm produce - cash account, 1901-1907 (Volume 9)
    - Personal family items - cash account, 1901-1907 (Volume 9)
    - Farm labor (employees - pay rates) - cash account, 1901-1907 (Volume 9)
    - File accounts, 1898 (Volume 9)
      - Employees - pay rates (Volume 9)
    - Mrs. George W. Raymond accounts, 1903-1905 (Volume 9)
    - Farm receipts, 1904-1905 (Volume 9)
    - Dry House accounts, 1902-1903 (Volume 9)
    - Asparagus account, 1899 (Volume 9)
    - Clarinda Miller Est. account, 1898-1907 (Volume 9)
- Series II. Miscellaneous records, 7 vols., 1867-1926
  - The Farmer's Journal, 1867-1905
    - C.C. Raymond's [?] Business Transactions of farm & family:
      - Inventory of Property (Volume 1)
      - Expenses of Family (Volume 1)
      - Incidental expenses (Volume 1)
      - Expenses in Cultivating Farm (Volume 1)
      - Paid for Permanent Improvements on Farm (Volume 1)
      - Register of Employees (Volume 1)
      - Sales of Farm Products (Volume 1)
      - Record of all Crops Cultivated (Volume 1)
      - Live Stock Register (Volume 1)
      - Cash Account (Volume 1)
      - General Accounts (Volume 1)
      - Bills Receivable (Volume 1)
      - Bills Payable (Volume 1)
      - Summary or Balance Sheet (Volume 1)
      - Record of Agricultural Fairs (Volume 1)
      - Rates of Postage (Volume 1)
      - Training Colts (Volume 1)
      - Breeding Animals for Meat (Volume 1)
      - Table of the Rates of Interest with Rule for casting (Volume 1)
      - Contract with Employee (Volume 1)
      - Memoranda (Volume 1)
  - Order Book - order forms for Raymond Bros., George Raymond Nurseryman, July 10, 1872-Feb. 2, 1874 (Volume 2)
  - Accountant's Cash Book, Feb. 19, 1881-Dec. 10, 1886 (Volume 3)
  - Memoranda (title on cover) - small brown leather cover; no clasp - C.C. Raymond accounts with Curtice Brothers for cherries, 1884 (Volume 4)
  - Darrow's Weekly Pocket Time Book - Workmen's names and hours a week, 1887-1908 (Volume 5)
  - Ledger - black leather cover (G.W. Raymond) - Pasture records and accounts, cows, etc. (selling), May 1, 1898-Apr. 1, 1926 (Volume 6)
  - Ledger (Brown covering with red binding) - C.B. Raymond accounts, Oct. 1, 1907-July 1, 1909
    - In high school, probably senior year (Volume 7)
    - Accounts of school fare, notebooks, books, school dance, haircut, home game, etc. (Volume 7)
- Series III. Miscellaneous loose bills rendered and rough notes, Mar. 1, 1862-Mar. 20, 1947 and n.d.
  - 53 pcs. in jute folder